Register of the Vrangel' collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- SHTAB DOBROVOL'CHESKOI ARMII, 1918-1922 (Boxes 28-33)
  - (Group I, File 135)
    - Foreign relations of Russian government, 1918-1919
      - Correspondence
        - Struve, P., typescript copies
          - Denikin, Gen. A., February 25, 1919 (Folder 32)
          - Fedorov, M. (?), May 10, 1919 (Folder 33)
      - Vserossiiskii Natsional'nyi TSentr
        - "Zhurnal Zasedanii Pravleniia No. 2," Ekaterinodar, 12-13 March, 1919 (Folder 34)
        - Neratov, A., "Soobshchenie o mezhdunarodnoe polozhenii,", April 13, 1919 (Folder 35)
  - (Group I, File 136)
    - Special intelligence section "Azbuka". Material related to its establishment and operation
      - General. Includes business papers related to daily operations of the organization, internal reports and correspondence, typescript, October 1918-May 1919 (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
      - Correspondence
        - Denikin, Lieut.-Gen. A. to Gens. Franchet d'Esperey, Milne, Berthelot, and Ambassador S. Sazonov, typescript copy, undated (Folder 3)
        - Dragomirov, Gen. A. to V. Maklakov(?), holograph, January 11, 1919 (Folder 4)
        - German General Staff, Nachrichten-Bureau, Section M, R. Bauer to Predstavitel' Soveta Narodnykh Komissarov, Includes letter of Komissar I. Alekseev to Vysshii Voennyi Sovet, April 9, 1918, typescript copies with handwritten annotations, March 3-Apr. 9, 1918 (Folder 5)
        - Maklakov, V., typescript copies
          - Neratov, A., April 24, 1919 (Folder 6)
          - Stepanov, V., April 24, 1919 (Folder 7)
        - SHul'gin, V.
          - Outgoing
            - Official correspondence, mostly with General Staff Headquarters, typescript with holograph annotations, May-June, 1919 (Folder 8)
            - Bobrinskii, Count V., holograph, September 30, 1918 (Folder 9)
            - British Representative in Baku, includes information re Lockhart and Pike, typescript copy, Sept, 6, 1918 (Folder 10)
            - Dragomirov, Gen. A., typescript copy; September 15, 1918(?), typescript; October 29, 1918, typescript copy; February 6, 1919(?), typescript with holograph annotations, August 30, 1918 (Folder 11)
            - Stepanov, V., typescript drafts with holograph annotations; February 6, 1919, typescript; March 20, 1919, typescript with holograph annotation; October 24, 1919, typescript, January 6, 1919 (Folder 12)
            - Wilhelm II, Emperor of Germany, typescript draft,; co-author with M. Rodzianko and V. Stepanov, undated (Folder 13)
          - Incoming
            - General, January-December 1919 (Folder 14)
            - Alekseev, Gen. M., August 28, 1918 (Folder 15)
              Available on microfilm reel 44
            - Dragomirov, Gen. A., August 29, 1918 (Folder 16)
            - Nabokov, P. et al., undated (Folder 17)
        - Stepanov, V. to A. Savenkov, typescript copy, December 7, 1918 (Folder 18)
      - Financial records and receipts, typescript and handwritten material, January-November 1919 (Folder 19)
      - Personnel, typescript and handwritten material, January-November 1919
        - Lists of "Azbuka" agents and other personnel. Includes some salary figures (Folder 20)
        - Personal attestations and evaluations (Folder 21-22)
      - Reports
        - General, handwritten and typescript, 1918-1919 (Folder 23-24)
        - "Azbuka" intelligence agents. Material relates mostly to Natsional'nyi TSentr in Kiev, typescript, 1918-1919 (Folder 25-33)
      - Memoranda and declarations
        - General, "Prikaz po organizatsii Dobrovol'cheskoi Armii," typescript, August 6, 1919 (Folder 34)
        - Alekseev, Gen. M.(?), "Polozhenie ob Osobom Soveshchanie pri Verkhovnom Rukovoditele Dobrovol'cheskoi Armii," typescript (?), August 20, 1918 (Folder 35)
        - Astrov, N., "Deklaratsiia obshchestvennykh deiatelei v g. Ekaterinodare k gen. Bertelo," signed N. Astrov, V. Neratov, V. SHul'gin et al., typescript (in French), October 21, 1918 (Folder 36)
        - Neratov, A., "Obrashchenie Dobrovol'cheskoi Armii k Soiuznikam," typescript, March 29, 1919 (Folder 37)
        - SHul'gin, V.
          - "Istoricheskaia spravka," typescript, May 19, 1919 (Folder 38)
          - "Polozhenie ob osobom soveshchanii pri verkhovnom glavnokomanduiushchem," typescript draft with holograph annotations, August 5, 1918 (Folder 39)
          - Report to Gen. A. Dragomirov, typescript, September 3, 1918 (Folder 40)
        - Transcripts of telephone conversations
          - Stepanov, V. with V. SHul'gin, typescript, January 9, 1919 (Folder 41)
          - Belousov, Maj.-Gen. D. with Capt. Shuber(?), Chief Officer of German forces on the Sea of Azov, typescript, undated (Folder 42)
- SHTAB GLAVNOKOMANDUIUSHCHAGO VOORUZHENNYMI SILAMI IUGA ROSSII (V.S.IU.R.), 1918-1922 (Boxes 34-55)
  Day-orders of Lieut.-Gen. A. Denikin and Baron P. Vrangel'; reports and internal files of "Azbuka," Otdel Propagandy pri Glavnokomanduiushchem and Razvedyvatel'noe Otdelenie pri Glavnokomanduiushchem V.S.IU.R.; political and military situation in Rumania and Bessarabia; political and military situation in the Ukraine under Skoropadskii, Petliura, the Germans and the Soviets; peasant revolts and activity of "Greens"; territories in South Russia and Crimea occupied by White Army: relations with Germans and Allies (French and British); military activity of Allies against Soviet forces; political and military situation in the Caucasus, Transcaucasia and the Caspian Sea; Vremennoe Sibirskoe Pravitel'stvo and Vserossiiskoe Vremennoe Pravitel'stvo (Ufa): printed documents, minutes of meetings and reports. Files 137-170, 180-186, 188.
  - (Group I, File 137, 138, 139, 140)
    - Day-orders of Commander-in-Chief, Lieut.-Gen. A. Denikin, printed copies, 1919
      - Ekaterinodar
        - No. 15-213, January1-31 (Box 34, Folder 1)
        - No. 218-679, February 2-April 13 (Folder 2)
        - No. 680-772, April 13-28 (Folder 3)
        - No. 799-910, May 3-14 (Folder 4)
        - No. 911-985, May 16-23 (Folder 5)
          Available on microfilm reel 45
        - Miscellaneous, June 9-27 (Folder 6)
        - No. 1083-1163, June 1-6 (Folder 7)
        - No. 1164-1220, June 7-13 (Folder 8)
        - No. 1221-1289, June 13-18 (Folder 9)
        - No. 1390-1474, July 2-10 (Box 35, Folder 1)
        - No. 1475-1538, July 10-13 (Folder 2)
      - Taganrog, No. 1539-, 1749, July 22-27 (Folder 3-4)
  - (Group I, File 141)
    - "Azbuka," reports of intelligence agents, typescript
      - Kiev, includes correspondence and documents of Ukrainian Foreign Ministry; composition and disposition of Red Army and German troops; correspondence with Donskoi Ataman Krasnov; transcripts of conversations between K. Rakovskii-G. CHicherin and K. Rakovskii-K. Radek (6), August 1918-December 1919 (Box 35, Folder 5-14)
        Available on microfilm reel 46
      - Georgia, August 18, 1919 (Folder 15)
      - Northern Armies, October 1918 (Folder 16)
    - Information Bulletin, "K natsional'nomu edineniiu grazhdane," No. 2-3, typescript, April-May 1919 (Folder 17)
    - Leaflet, "Usloviia sluzhby v IUzhnoi Armii," printed copy, Kiev, undated (Folder 18)
  - (Group I, File 142)
    - Inquest into treasonable and criminal activity of Adm. Sergeev, Commander of Caspian Flotilla. Includes formal accusation of Lieut.-Gen. Tolstov, Ataman of Cossack Army of the Urals; descriptions of Ural campaigns; corruption in military and civilian administration of Caspian region; relations with Allies, typescript and handwritten, May 31, 1922-August 13, 1923 (Box 36, Folder 1-6)
  - (Group I, File 143)
    - Rumania and Bessarabia, 1918
      - Upravlenie Nachal'nika Dorozhnykh Rabot Rumynskoi Armii, miscellaneous material, including correspondence and reports, typescript, January-April (Box 36, Folder 7-9)
        Available on microfilm reel 47
      - "Kishinevskaia mestnaia demobilizatsionnaia komissiia," miscellaneous material, including reports re general situation in Rumania and Bessarabia, typescript, March (Folder 10)
    - Jassy Conference
      - Reports, typescript
        - General, in French, November (Folder 11)
        - "IAsskoe soveshchanie,", undated (Folder 12)
        - List of participants, including members of "Sovet Gosudarstvennago Ob"edineniia Rossii" (Folder 13)
      - "Natsional'nyi TSentr" and "Soiuz Vozrozhdeniia Rossii," typescript
        - Minutes of meetings, No. 1-23, Russian delegation, November 16-December 5 (Folder 14-15)
        - Protocols of meetings between Russian delegation and Allied representatives, November 17 and 23 (Folder 16)
        - Address of Russian delegation to Allies, November 17 (Folder 17)
    - Reports
      - General, French military aid under Gen. Berthelot, typescript, December (Folder 18)
      - "Azbuka," report of intelligence agent, handwritten (Folder 19)
      - Otdel Propagandy Osobago Soveshchaniia pri Glavnokomanduiushchem V.S.IU.R. (O.S.V.A.G.), re (Folder 20)
        - Bessarabia, typescript, undated
  - (Group I, File 144)
    - Sfatul Tarii, printed copies, February 27-March 31, 1918 (Box 37)
  - (Group I, File 145)
    - Ukraine, Peasant revolts against Soviet rule; Petliura and the Galician Army. Intelligence reports and newspaper clippings re various revolts, their cause and aims, the mood of the peasantry; eyewitness accounts of rebel leaders Zelenyi, CHaikovskii, Nestor Makhno, Makhno Sagaidachnyi, Angel, Kotsura, Shestak, Sokolovskii, Veselovskii, Ataman Grigoriev, Petliura, Simon. Revolts of German colonists. Miscellaneous material re Galician Army in Ukrainian and German. Typescript and handwritten, 1919 (Box 37)
      - General (Box 38, Folder 1-3)
        Available on microfilm reel 48
      - Grigoriev (Folder 4-5)
      - Petliura (Folder 6-7)
    - Commandement en Chef des Armées Alliées en Orient, reports
      - "Déclaration du Lieutenant-Colonel Docteur Troitzky, sous-chef du Service de Santé des Troupes Polonaises en Russie," typescript, undated (Folder 8)
      - Franchet d'Esperey, Gen., to Agent de Liaison du Haut Commandement Français en Orient, "Compte-Rendu," typescript French text and handwritten Russian translation, August 22 (Folder 9)
    - Printed matter
      - "Prikazi do vporiadu pikhoti Zakhidno-Ukrainskoi Narodnoi Respubliki,", 1918 (Folder 10)
      - Vechernee Vremia, KHar'kov, August 12, 14, 1919 (Folder 11)
    - Proclamations. SHtab partizanskikh Otriadiv Levoberezhnoi Ukrainy, printed copy, undated and Sovet Raboche-Krestianskoi Oborony Ukrainy, printed copy, August 28, 1919 (Folder 12)
  - (Group I, File 146)
    - Military fronts, 1919
      - Intelligence reports
        - Nachal'nik Khar'kovskago Razvedyvatel'nago Punkta. Composition and strength of Soviet armed forces, includes diagrams and maps,; KHar'kov; Volunteer Army and administration, their condition, relations with workers and peasants, the problem of propaganda and press, activities of opposition parties; Briansk front; Kursk-Orel-Tula-Voronezh front; disposition, strength and condition of Soviet armed forces, recruitment into Red Army, mood of urban and rural population; Mamontov raid and its effect on Soviet morale; Moscow, living conditions and mood of population. Handwritten and typescript material, January-November 1919, July-October (Box 38, Folder 13-21)
        - Nachal'nik Razvedyvatel'nago Punkta Donskoi Oblasti, Novocherkassk. Political situation in Don region: monarchist groups, Ataman Krasnov, influence of Germans and Allies; disposition and strength of Soviet troops, Voronezh front; composition and training of Soviet troops; peasant uprisings against Soviet occupation and relation of various classes of peasants to Soviet power; situation in Taganrog. Typescript, June 1919 (Folder 22-24)
        - "Azbuka," Otdelenie pri stavke Glavnokomanduiushchago, Ekaterinodar, list of "Azbuka" staff; creation of "Natsional'nyi TSentr"; military situation, typescript, undated (Folder 25)
      - Proclamations. "K ofitseram belykh armii," Politicheskii Otdel Revoliutsionnogo Voennogo Soveta IUzhnogo fronta, undated and "Ob"iavlenie Komanduiushchago Voiskami Poltavskago Otriada," Kiev, October 26, 1919 (Folder 26)
  - (Group I, File 147)
    - Intelligence reports, Razvedyvatl'noe Otdelenie SHtaba Glavnokomanduiushchago, Voenno-Agenturnyia Svodki. Includes letters from intelligence agents, eyewitness reports and newspaper clippings re: general situation in Soviet occupied territory, including reports and letters from Moscow; Bolshevik terror, typescript excerpt from Izvestiia,; Red Army, organization and deployment; Caucasus, including Armenia and Georgia; "Latyshskie bol'sheviki v Rossii"; Ukraine, Natsional'nyi TSentr; German colonists, Volga region; Poland, Latvia and Byelorussia; Jewish role in the Revolution; information received from foreign missions (French and British); transmissions of Soviet radio news; Maritime Provinces and the Far East. Handwritten and typescript material, 1919, October 1919 (Box 39, Folder 1-13)
      Available on microfilm reel 49
    - Leaflet, "Programma Russkoi Narodnoi Dobrovol'cheskoi Armii," printed copy, undated (Folder 14)
  - (Group I, File 148)
    - Intelligence reports, Razvedyvatel'noe Otdelenie SHtaba Glavnokomanduiushchago re Petliura and Ukrainian separatism. Includes reports of foreign missions and eyewitness accounts; composition and disposition of Petliura's army; Polish-Ukrainian negotiations; excerpts from Polish press; internal political situation in Ukraine; Odessa; Kiev; Rumania; Red Army, disposition in south; Galician troops, disposition and activity; miscellaneous Green organizations, typescript and handwritten, June-December 1919 (Box 39, Folder 15-20)
    - Intelligence reports, contd. (Box 40, Folder 1-14)
      Available on microfilm reel 50
    - Printed matter
      - Leaflets and proclamations in Ukrainian, 1919 (Folder 15)
        Available on microfilm reel 51
      - Pamphlet, Ukrainsko Slovo, No. 1, printed copy, Sophia, 1919 (Folder 16)
  - (Group I, File 149)
    - Reports of special intelligence section, "Azbuka" and Razvedyvatel'noe Otdelenie SHtaba Glavnokomanduiushchago. Political and military situation of "Directory"; Makhno; Vinnichenko-Petliura crisis; fall of Getman Skoropadskii, establishment of "Directory"; situation in Odessa; situation in KHar'kov; Vinnichenko-Petliura break, fall of Directory; Kiev under Bolshevik control; KHar'kov, Poltava province and Ekaterinoslav under Bolshevik control; Kiev, right-wing organizations; general political and military situation in the Ukraine, Azov-Dnepr Front. Typescript and handwritten material, January-February December 1918-January 1919 (Box 40, Folder 17-26)
    - Reports of special intelligence section, "Azbuka" and Razvedyvatel'noe Otdlenie SHtaba Glavnokomanduiushchago, contd. (Box 41, Folder 1-6)
  - (Group I, File 150)
    - Intelligence reports, Razvedyvatel'noe Otdelenie SHtaba Glavnokomanduiushchago. Makhno; general situation in Odessa; military situation on Southern Front; Rostov-na-Donu; Bol'shoi Voiskovoi Krug, minutes of meetings, plans for future government; Taganrog, conditions among workers in factories; Bolshevik troops in TSaritsyn; Sevastopol'; Rostov; peasant uprisings; Bolshevik occupation of Lugansk region; disposition of troops; condition of Volunteer Army; monarchist organizations; German propaganda; relations with French and British. Typescript and handwritten material, December 1918-March 1919 (Box 41, Folder 7-19)
      Folders 7-13 available on microfilm reel 51; folders 14-19 on reel 52.
  - (Group I, File 151)
    - Reports of special intelligence section "Azbuka". Kiev under Hetman Skoropadsky; "Krymskoe kraevoe pravitel'stvo"; transcipts of Allied telegrams re German ships in Black Sea and occupation of German held Crimean territories by Allies, includes communication with Vice-Admiral Hopman; Sevastopol and the Allies; Kiev: internal politics, problem of separatism, rise of Petliura, Graf Keller, Russkii Natsional'nyi TSentr; Bolshevik plans for winter campaign, 1918; condition and disposition of Soviet troops; "Vserossiiskii Natsional'nyi TSentr o soveshchanii na Printsevykh Ostrovakh"; Bolshevik occupation of Kiev, organization and condition of Red Army, pogroms by Red Army; peasant uprisings, Makhno, Grigoriev, Zelenyi, their aims and composition; uprisings among German colonists; Bolshevik occupation of Odessa; contacts between Volunteer Army and Balkan nations; situation in Moscow; situation in Voronezh. Typescript and handwritten material, November 1918-July 1919 (Box 41, Folder 20-24)
      Available on microfilm reel 52
    - Intelligence reports, contd. (Box 42, Folder 1-16)
      Folders 1-6 available on microfilm reel 52; folders 7-16 on reel 53.
    - Correspondence, typescript copies
      - Maklakov, V.
        - Panina, S.; Stepanov, V.; Astrov, N., April 30, 1919 (Folder 17)
          Available on microfilm reel 53
        - Stepanov, V., March 7, 1919 (Folder 18)
        - Vinaver, M., March 7, 1919 (Folder 19)
      - Stepanov, V. to V. Maklakov, April 11, 1919 (Folder 20)
    - Russkoe Telegrafnoe Agenstvo, "Russagent," reports, typescript, June 29-July 12, 1919 (Folder 21)
  - (Group I, File 152)
    - Reports of special intelligence section "Azbuka". Situation in Sevastopol; transfer of German held Russian vessels to Allies, includes Russian translations of German documents; transcripts of "Radio Osmanie" messages; evacuation of German troops and transfer of Sevastopol to Allied and Russian Volunteer Army control; Partiia sotsialistov-revoliutsionerov, activities in Sevastopol... Secret report re occupation of Odessa by Volunteer Army; Bessarabia; Simferopol; transcripts of telephone and radio conversations between Volunteer Army and Crimean Regional Government, includes V. Stepanov, M. Vinaver, V. Nabokov, N. Astrov; Sevastopol under Allied occupation; situation in Turkestan; Bolshevik propaganda among Allied sailors in Sevastopol; fate of White naval officers after Bolshevik takeover of Sevastopol. Typescript and handwritten material, September 22, 1918-June 20, 1919 (Box 42, Folder 22-28)
    - Essays
      - Authors unknown
        - Untitled, typescript, undated (Folder 29)
        - "'Chto takoe bol'shevizm'. Zapiska podannaia inostrantsam nashei tsenzuroi," holograph (in French), undated (Folder 30)
        - "Glavnyia osnovaniia formirovaniia armii v iuzhnoi Rossii," typescript, undated (Folder 31)
        - "Ob organizatsii natsional'noi promyshlenosti i natsional'nago promyshlennago kapitala," holograph, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 54
        - "Osnovnaia prichina russkoi revoliutsii Sotsiologicheskii etiud," typescript, 1919, 1917 (Folder 2)
        - "Pis'mo o Dobrovol'cheskoi armii," holograph, undated (Folder 3)
        - "Problema sozdaniia vlasti," typescript, undated (Folder 4)
        - "The Situation in South Russia," typescript, January 19, 1920 (Folder 5)
        - "Tainy bol'shevistskoi inkvizitsii. Russkiia chrezvychaiki i ikh rabota," handwritten, undated (Folder 6)
        - "Zapiska o kharaktere pomoshchi, kotoruiu dolzhny okazat' soiuzniki Rossii," typescript, undated (Folder 7)
        - "Zapiska ob interventsii v Rossii," typescript, undated (Folder 8)
      - Bernadskii, M., "Perspektivy denezhnoi reformy," typescript, undated (Folder 9)
      - Guchkov, A., "Bor'ba v Rossii s bol'shevizmom i eia perspektivy," typescript, January 1919 (Folder 10)
      - Novgorodtsev, P., "O mezhdunarodnoi opasnosti bol'shevizma," typescript, January 1919 (Folder 11)
      - Struve, P., "Nekotoryia soobrazheniia o mirovom politicheskom polozhenii...," typescript, June, 1919 (Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, typescript copies
      - Il'in, S.
        - Open letter, November 16, 1922 (Folder 13)
        - KHolmnsen, Lieut.-Gen. I., July 12, 1922 (Folder 14)
      - Maklakov, M.
        - Neratov, A., October 15, 1920 (Folder 15)
        - Paléologue, M., September 14, 1920 (Folder 16)
      - Petrunkevich, I. to N. Astrov, December 24, 1918 and March 1-5, 1919 (Folder 17)
      - Stepanov, V.
        - Denikin, General A., November 15, 1918 (Folder 18)
        - Miliukov, P., December 27, 1918 (Folder 19)
      - Teslenko, N. to V. Stepanov, February 7, 1918 (Folder 20)
    - Russkii Natsional'nyi Komitet v Parizhe
      - Circular letter, printed copy, March 25, 1921 (Folder 21)
      - Minutes of meetings, typescript, April 21, 28 and May 5, 1922 (Folder 22)
      - "Vypiska iz postanovleniia.." and address, "Russkie voiny,", December 1922, January 1923 (Folder 23)
    - Drafts of financial agreements between French government and V.S.IU.R., typescript, undated (Folder 24)
  - (Group I, File 153)
    - Siberia, Volga Region, Transcaucasia and Transcaspia, 1918-1919
      - Volga region and Siberia
        - Vremennoe Sibirskoe Pravitel'stvo. Documents under signature of P. Vologodskii, I. Mikhailov, G. Patushinskii and M. Shatilov, typescript copies
          - General, undated (Documents No. 2, 9) (Box 43, Folder 25)
          - "Chlenam Zapadno-Sibirskago Komissariata... Gramota," (Document No. 3), June 30, 1918 (Folder 26)
          - "Komanduiushchemu Zapadno-Sibirskoi otdel'noi armieii polkovniku Grishinu-Almazovu," (Document No. 4), June 30, 1918 (Folder 27)
          - "Doblestnym chekho-slovatskim eshelonam. Gramota...," (Document No. 5), undated (Folder 28)
          - "Ko vsem grazhdanam," (Document No. 6), undated (Folder 29)
        - Vserossiiskoe Vremennoe Pravitel'stvo (Ufa)
          - General, typescript copies
            - "Gramota. Vserosiiskago Vremennago Pravitel'stva ko vsem narodam Rossii,", September 1918 (Folder 30)
            - Ufimskoe Gosudarstvennoe Soveshchanie, minutes of meetings, September 12, 18, 1918 (Folder 31)
            - "Prikaz Verkhovnago Glavnokomanduiushchago Vserossiiskago Vremennago Pravitel'stva,", September 24, 1918 (Folder 32)
            - S"ezd chlenov Uchreditel'nago Sobraniia. Otkrytie s'ezda, September 26 (Folder 33)
          - Correspondence
            - Belorussov, A. to friends, typescript copy, March 10, 1919 (Folder 34)
            - Kiselev, N. to V. Stepanov, March 9-22 1919 (Folder 35)
            - Novikov to members of Denikin government, typescript copy, March 19, 1919 (Folder 36)
            - Pepeliaev, V. to Natsional'nyi TSentr, typescript copy, undated (Folder 37)
            - Shardetskii, V. to N. Astrov et al, typescript copy, March 25, 1919 (Folder 38)
            - Vinogradov, V. to friends, typescript copy, March 1919 (Folder 39)
          - Reports, typescript copies
            - General, undated (Folder 40)
            - "Pravda o zavolzhskoi Rossii,", April 9, 1918 (Folder 41)
            - "Doklad gv. polkovnika Mollera,", undated (Folder 42)
            - "Admiral Kolchak v Omske,", undated (Folder 43)
            - "Soobshchenie polkovnika Egorova o polozhenii v Sibiri,", April 13, 1919 (Folder 44)
            - "Soobshchenie generala Fluga o polozhenii v Sibiri,", April 20, 1919 (Folder 45)
      - Transcaucasia and Transcaspia
        - Reports, typescript copies
          - General, undated (Folder 46)
          - Artsimovich, P., "Zakavkazie v nashi dni...Doklad sdelannyi...Rossiiskomu Natsional'nomu Tsemtru v Ekaterinodare,", February 7, 1919 (Folder 47)
          - CHaikovskii, Col. N., "Kratkii obzor istorii vzaimootnoshenii Dobrovol'cheskoi Armii s Gruziei po voprosu o sochinskom okruge. ," report to head of British military mission in Ekaterinodar, Lt.-Gen. Briggs, 1918-1919 (Folder 48)
          - Dzhunkovskii, E., "Soobshchenie predstavitelia vremennago pravitel'stva zakaspiiskago kraia v Askhabade,", undated (Folder 49)
          - Erdeli, Gen. I., "Soobshchenie...o ego komandirovke v Zakavkaz'e,", April 13, 1919 (Folder 50)